Bhavesh Wadhwani

SOFTWARE ENGINEER + DATA SCIENTIST + GOOGLE CLOUD CERTIFIED

🛮 (+91) 899-911-6241 | 🗷 bhaveshwadhwani 14@gmail.com | 🎁 bhaveshwadhwani.github.io | 🖸 bhaveshwadhwani | 🛅 bhaveshwadhwani

"Be the change that you want to see in the world."

Summary _

Results-oriented Data Scientist with 3+ years of work experience in the IT industry. Experienced in Machine-learning, Deep Learning, Computer Vision, Natural Language Processing (NLP), processing real-time data. Recently have verified my Data Engineering skills too by passing the GCP Professional Data Engineer Exam. Having worked on GCP, Azure, AWS Cloud platforms for various development and deployment projects enables me to have a nice view of the current phase of technology in the industry.

Work Experience _____

Nihilent Ltd. Pune, India

SOFTWARE ENGINEER - DATA SCIENTIST

Nov. 2019 - Present

- Helping clients to make better business decisions based on insights from their data.
- Developed end-to-end machine learning prototypes and scaled them to run in production environments, increased efficiency by 23%.
- Designed an overall architecture and pipelines of the Machine Learning / Deep Learning based applications with the micro-services architecture.
- Implemented solutions from scratch for data science, working on whole life cycle of solutions.
- Deployed production ready scalable models for internet scale data.
- · Skills/Tools used in Job: Azure/GCP/AWS platforms, Git, Jupyter, Python, Machine Learning, Deep Learning, Kubernetes, Docker

Infosys Pune, India

Systems Engineer Dec. 2017 - Jun. 2019

- Working to help ONGC Client (One of top 10 companies in Fortune 500) to reduce cost and improve efficiency for servers.
- Certified from Infosys for Python, SQL, Machine Learning, Deep Learning.
- As part of Infosys NIA OPS-Analytics team we target to improve performance and create high business value and we successfully reduced manual work to 60% by atomizing solutions.
- Cleaned and Analyzed text data using Python, NLP techniques, ML Algorithms.
- · Improved performance of servers by 8% and reduce critical alerts by 10% by using previous event alert log data using Machine Learning.

Eventbeep Entertainment

Pune, India

SOFTWARE ENGINEER - WEB DEVELOPER

June. 2017 - Dec. 2017

- Woked on a product "Ticketing platform for college and university events".
- Full stack developer using technologies like Php, codeignitor framework, javascript, html, css, bootstrap.
- Responsible for developing new features on website with leading a team of 5 interns.
- Few key features in which I had contributed in the product were Integrating payment gateways to website, SMS and Email integration for ticketing platform, built dynamic display for events with minimal latency.

Skills_

Programming: Python

Database: MS-SQL, MySQL, SQLite, Mongo DB, BigQuery **Scientific Computing Frameworks:** Numpy, SciPy, Pandas, Dask, GeoPandas

ML Toolbox: Sklearn, NLTK, OpenCV, Keras, Tensorflow, Azure ML, Pytorch, Azure ML Studio

Deployment Toolbox: Azure ML, GCP AI Platform, AWS Sagemaker, Docker, Kubeflow, Flask

Data Visualization Tools: Plotly, Matplotlib, Seaborn

Cloud Platforms: Google Cloud Platform(GCP), Azure, AWS, Google Colab, Heroku

Project Dev. Tools: Jupyter Notebook, Github, VSCode IDE, Machine Learning Algorithms, Deep Learning Techinques

Certifications

INTERNATIONAL

2020	Certification, Google Cloud Professional Data Engineer [See the Certificate]	Google Cloud
2020	Certification , Applied Machine Learning & Deep Learning Course [See the Certificate]	AAIC , India
2020	Certification, Computer Vision Nanodegree [See the Certificate]	UDACITY, U.S.A
2020	Certification, Deep Learning Nanodegree [See the Certificate]	UDACITY, U.S.A
2020	Certification , Tensorflow in Practice Specialization [See the Certificate]	Coursera, U.S.A
2020	Certification, Deep Learning Specialization [See the Certificate]	Coursera, U.S.A

Writing.

Image Captioning in Python with Keras

Medium Blog Page

TECHNICAL BLOG WRITER

Sep. 2019

• END TO END approach for Image Captioning, starting right from data collection up to model building and making predictions on model.

Education

Maharashtra Institute of Technology (University of Pune)

Pune, India

B.E. IN INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY

June. 2013 - June. 2017

• Machine Learning, Deep Learning, IoT, Cloud Computing, Software Engineering, Data Structures and Algorithms, Web Technologies.